## **Ahmed Daoud**

Oman | +968 9570 1119

diyab100@gmail.com

## **Professional Summary**

A professional Deputy HSE Manager / Engineer with around 15 years of experience in the field, holder of a bachelor's degree in Petroleum Engineering, and have attended multiple courses in the industry. Gained practical experience in HSE. Supports the Top Management in the Organization's roles and responsibilities definition, for what concerns safety aspects.

#### **Professional strengths include:**

- Site Engineering.
- Accountability & Continuous Improvement.
- Training & Development.
- Incident Investigation.
- Team Supervision.
- Management & Team Building.
- Operations Management.
- Convincing Presentations.
- Risk Assessment.
- Hazard & Risk Assessments.

#### **Experience**

## Azhar Afar Trading - Sultanate of Oman - May 2018 - Present

#### **HSE Manager**

Clients: Petroleum Development Oman (PDO), Fahud Oilfield Services (FOS), Weatherford International, Special Oilfield Services (SOS).

- Preparing and enforcing policies to establish a culture of health and safety.
- Evaluating practices, procedures, and facilities to assess risk and adherence to the law.
- Conduct training and presentations for health and safety matters and accident prevention.
- Monitor compliance with policies and laws by inspecting employees and operations.
- Recommend solutions to issues, improvement opportunities, or new prevention measures.

# Osman International (Adroit Training Institute) - Sultanate of Oman - Sep 2016 - Apr 2018

## Senior HSE Engineer / HSE Instructor

Clients: Petroleum Development Oman (PDO), Great Wall Drilling Company (GWDC), and Other Technical Organizations.

- Responsible for teaching HSE classes and conducting small group tutoring sessions in a way
  that facilitates successful participant interaction and retention and creates a quality learning
  experience.
- Maintain documentation of evaluation, ongoing instructional programs, student progress, and communications by 90%.
- Prepare reports and collect data requested by the Director of Education and required by private and public funders up to 95%

National Upstream Solution Co. - Khartoum, Republic of Sudan - Jan 2012 - May 2016

## Senior HSE Engineer

Clients: Greater Nile Petroleum Operating Company (GNPOC), PETRONAS, and Petrodar Operating Company (PDOC).

- Complete 100% Commissioning & Per-commissioning in CPF of Heigleg Petroleum Field (Central Production Facility).
- Reported 100% to the QHSE Director, presented weekly/monthly HSE reports, and regularly audited rig equipment to ensure safety standards were met.
- Conducted regular safety meetings with the crew, provided basic HSE training, and suitable adequate PPE on the rig site and all crew and visitors followed the company's PPE policies to achieve 0.0% Incidents.
- The presence of environmental codes and procedures was effectively implemented to comply 100% with governmental and international regulations.
- Led full-scale (100%) investigations of accidents and near-miss incidents, determined, and prepared corrective actions, and ensured all action items were implemented.

Heigleg Petroleum Co. - Khartoum, Republic of Sudan - Nov 2008 - Dec 2011

#### **HSE Engineer**

Clients: Greater Nile Petroleum Operating Company (GNPOC), and Petrodar Operating Company (PDOC).

Operation & Maintenance period of ADAR (FPF) Field Production Facility block 3&7 Melut

- Basin Oil development project.
- Supported the QHSE Manager/Drilling Superintendent in implementing and maintaining effective safety policies – efforts resulted in no (0%) LTI (Lost Time Incidents).
- Provided 100 % training on the Safety Management System updated and maintained training matrix and scheduled crew members for external training.

#### **Education**

Bachelor's Degree in Petroleum Engineering – 2008

Sudan University of Science & Technology - Khartoum, Republic of Sudan

#### **Courses**

Golden Rule of Safety Awareness.

Job Safety Analysis.

General Site Safety Environmental Control & Monitoring.

Basic Fire Fighting.

H2S Awareness and Escape Certified Gas Tester.

Advanced Safety Auditing.

Basic First Aid Course HS&E Workshop.

#### **Certifications**

American Heart Association (AHA), Heart Saver Instructor, First Aid, CPR AED

**NEBOSH IGC** 

**IOSH Managing Safely** 

ISO 14000:2004

ISO 9000:2008

OSHA Construction (1926)

**COSHH Risk Assessor Certificate** 

OHSAS 18000:2007

**Defensive Driving** 

Hazard & Risk identification & Analysis

Appointed Person Certificate BS7121

Basic Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation & First Aid.

## Languages

Arabic: Native

English: Full Professional Proficiency